<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design | Maia McCormick]]></title>
  <link href="http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maiamcc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-11T11:35:26-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://maiamcc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maia Remez McCormick]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design Principles from Liz]]></title>
    <link href="http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/2014/12/01/design-principles-from-liz/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T12:17:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/2014/12/01/design-principles-from-liz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other week, I chatted with the fabulous <a href="//lizstarin.com">Liz Starin</a> and picked her aesthetically-enabled brain about fonts and layouts for websites. Below is some stuff I learned from our design adventures, both wisdom straight from her and stuff I picked up from my experience overhauling fonts and layout: <!-- more --></p>

<ul>
<li>x-height is a unit referring to how tall the letter ‘x’ is in a given font. The larger the x-height, the easier to read on-screen. (Some fonts with small x-heights include Garamond and Futura.)</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/xheight.gif" alt="A shiny graphic about x-height" />
Graphic found in PAPress’s <a href="//www.papress.com/thinkingwithtype/index.htm">Thinking with Type</a> project.</p>

<ul>
<li>serifs are generally the best choice for body text—they tend to be more readable on-screen.</li>
<li>in CSS, you can set <code>line-height</code>, which controls the space between lines of text. Increasing line spacing just a bit can improve readability a <em>lot</em>.</li>
<li>when picking a font, it’s helpful to have some adjectives in mind, rather than blindly scanning around for a font that you like. At the very least, it will give you a place to start.</li>
<li><a href="//www.google.com/fonts">Google Fonts</a> is an incredible thing.</li>
<li>a surprisingly good way to gauge whether a font has the intended effect: imagine you got a wedding invitation written in that font, and think of what that invitation would say about the people getting married. Is that the image you want your website/blog/pony-rental business to convey?</li>
<li>rounded fonts tend to be more playful. Or is it that playful fonts tend to be more rounded? In any case, if you’re looking for something with a “playful” vibe (like I was), rounded-ness is a good feature to start looking for.</li>
<li>you can achieve a lot of variety with the same font. (In fact, you WANT to achieve a lot of variety with the same font—if no variety, your site looks boring, and if variety achieved by different fonts, your site looks like it got sloppy-drunk and made a bunch of poor decisions at the font bar.) Some ways to achieve variety within the same font: varying font weight (CSS: <code>font-weight</code>), case (upper/lower/title—CSS: <code>text-transform</code>), and letter spacing (CSS: <code>letter-spacing</code>), to name a few.</li>
<li>I had (and still have) massive struggles with making favicons that look like anything besides a blob. A feature I hadn’t consciously thought to look at was <em>light/dark contrast</em>. As a quick way of checking, Liz suggests putting the image in grayscale and seeing if it looks decent like that.</li>
<li>some fonting resources: <a href="//alistapart.com/">A List Apart</a> and <a href="//www.smashingmagazine.com/">Smashing Magazine</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
