<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: soft skills | Maia McCormick]]></title>
  <link href="http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/categories/soft-skills/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://maiamcc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-06-27T11:49:12-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://maiamcc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maia Remez McCormick]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Hunting While Day-Jobbing]]></title>
    <link href="http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/2021/06/27/job-hunting/"/>
    <updated>2021-06-27T12:22:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/2021/06/27/job-hunting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewing is stressful enough, but interviewing <em>while</em> doing your day job?<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> Yikes!</p>

<p><img src="/images/job-hunting/yikea.jpeg" alt="Yikea (like Ikea, but for Yikes)" /></p>

<p>Well, I just did it,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> and I&rsquo;m here to tell you that it&rsquo;s totally doable! In this post, I share my thoughts on interview prep, minimizing day job disruptions, keeping up appearances at work, etc.<!-- more --></p>

<p>This last time around the interview cycle, I was still working at a company I wanted to do right by, but a lot of the advice below applies whether your aim is &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t want to fuck over my current coworkers&rdquo; or &ldquo;I want to not burn bridges so I can get a recommendation from these people in future&rdquo;. (If you have no fucks left to give about your current job, then go nuts!)</p>

<p>As always, take my advice with a grain of salt, as <a href="/images/job-hunting/no-idea.png">I have no idea what I&rsquo;m doing</a>. Got more tips? Leave a comment below! Now, without further ado, I present:</p>

<h2>Maia&rsquo;s Tips and Tricks for Job Hunting While Day-Jobbing</h2>

<h3>Don&rsquo;t Panic</h3>

<p><img src="/images/job-hunting/dont-panic.jpg" alt="Don't Panic (from Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy)" />
No seriously, don&rsquo;t panic. It&rsquo;s gonna be okay. You&rsquo;re gonna start slowly and work your way up to the actual interviewing, you&rsquo;re gonna be smart about scheduling interviews to minimize disruption of your day job, and you are hireable and desirable and don&rsquo;t let that little jerk voice in your head tell you otherwise.</p>

<h3>Set Secrecy Levels to&hellip; Eh, Something</h3>

<p>If your current employer suspects that you&rsquo;re interviewing, it&rsquo;s not the worst thing<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>! Don&rsquo;t go shouting it from the rooftops, and try to be discrete, but also don&rsquo;t worry too hard about whether you&rsquo;re being conspicuous. You&rsquo;re probably being a lot less obvious than you think (your co-workers/bosses aren&rsquo;t actually scrutinizing you that closely). But also, if someone suspects that you&rsquo;re looking, whatever.</p>

<p>Remember that you don&rsquo;t need to explain your &ldquo;busy&rdquo; calendar blocks to anyone. Get in the habit early of not offering explanations&mdash;instead of &ldquo;Out of Office (dentist)&rdquo;, just mark &ldquo;Out of Office&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t tell your boss(es) before you&rsquo;re ready to give notice, but you can absolutely tell one or two trusted coworkers that you’re looking (this can be great moral support). Consider who you will ask for a reference, and consider telling them that you&rsquo;re job hunting a little in advance of actually asking for the reference.</p>

<h3>Minimizing Work Disruptions</h3>

<p>Job hunting while working a job is tricky but absolutely doable. There will be some disruption to your day job, but with careful planning and good bookkeeping, you can minimize both that disruption, and the stress and guilt that sometimes comes with it.</p>

<p>Step 1 is to accept that you won&rsquo;t be doing your day job at full capacity while interviewing. That&rsquo;s okay. Set expectations at work: keep people updated on your project timelines as they inevitably fall a little behind, and don&rsquo;t bite off more work than you can chew. Ideally, you can make an excuse of the form &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve got some personal stuff going on right now so I&rsquo;ll be working a little under capacity.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s it, that&rsquo;s all they need to know. Resist the instinct to give more details or make more excuses&mdash;you&rsquo;re allowed to have a life outside of work.</p>

<p>This may be a no-brainer, but make sure that any interviews etc. are marked as &ldquo;busy&rdquo; on your work calendar&mdash;you don&rsquo;t want people trying to schedule meetings that you then have to decline. I heartily recommend using <a href="https://calendly.com/">Calendly</a> for scheduling.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup></p>

<p>To minimize disruption to your workday, take calls/interviews at the beginning or end of your workday if you can (or during your lunch hour). That said, respect your body&rsquo;s rhythms. If you&rsquo;re foggy in the mornings or if you start to flag in the afternoons, don&rsquo;t schedule technical interviews then.</p>

<h3>Interview Prep</h3>

<h4>Timeline</h4>

<p>If, like me, you&rsquo;re <em>super intimidated</em> by the prospect of job hunting, remember that you&rsquo;re allowed to start slow. You don&rsquo;t need to be 100% sure you want to leave or completely ready to do an onsite to start doing practice problems or to update your resume.</p>

<p>Something that worked well for me: as soon as I started thinking about job hunting, I put a recurring weekly 1 hour block of &ldquo;interview prep&rdquo; time on my calendar. It helped me make a little progress each week, without freaking out at all times about whether I &ldquo;should&rdquo; be prepping.</p>

<h4>Practice Interviews</h4>

<p>Below I give resources that you can use for self-study, but IMHO, by far the best way to prep for interviews is to do practice interviews with a real live human.</p>

<p>Reach out to your tech communities, old coworkers, friends in the industry, etc.&mdash;more than likely, there will be people willing to give you mock interviews in any of the above. In general, everyone in tech has had someone help them out in this capacity, so most of us are paying it forward and happy to help others!</p>

<h4>What to Prep</h4>

<h5>A. Resume</h5>

<p>Update your resume with all the cool stuff you&rsquo;ve been doing lately! I recommend writing down all of the interesting projects you&rsquo;ve done at this job; you&rsquo;ll only end up putting a few on your resume, but having a list of things you&rsquo;ve worked on lately will be helpful for preparing answers to behavioral questions (&ldquo;tell me about a time a project ran long&rdquo; etc.).</p>

<h5>B. System Design</h5>

<p>This is a big one the more senior you get. You should be able to talk in broad strokes about how you&rsquo;d design various systems, and be familiar (at least in passing) with database operations, caching, load balancing, etc.</p>

<p>Resources:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/madd86/awesome-system-design">Awesome System Design</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer">System Design Primer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/systems-design-for-interviews/">System Design for Interviews</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.educative.io/courses/grokking-the-system-design-interview">Grokking the System Design Interview</a></li>
<li>Any number of system design/tech podcasts<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></li>
</ul>


<h5>C. Coding &amp; Algorithms</h5>

<p>I was pleasantly surprised that few of my companies asked me algorithm-heavy &ldquo;invert this binary tree&rdquo;-type problems, but it&rsquo;s good to be prepared. Generally for senior roles, you should focus on being able to code cleanly; narrating your thought process as you go; and discussing the time and space complexity of your solutions.</p>

<p>Some additional things that will help you in coding interviews:</p>

<ol>
<li>liberal use of TODOs so you don&rsquo;t bog yourself down (e.g. &ldquo;there&rsquo;s probably an edge case here, but let me finish the rest of the function and I&rsquo;ll come back to it&rdquo;)</li>
<li>willingness to ask questions/use Google/admit when you don&rsquo;t know stuff (&ldquo;ugh, is the function <code>.sort()</code> or <code>.sorted()</code>? Well, that&rsquo;s the sort of thing I&rsquo;d Google, let&rsquo;s assume it&rsquo;s <code>.sort()</code> for now&hellip;&rdquo;).</li>
</ol>


<p>Resources:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://interviews.school/">interviews.school</a></li>
<li><a href="https://runestone.academy/runestone/books/published/pythonds/index.html">Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures using Python</a></li>
<li><a href="https://leetcode.com/">Leetcode</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/dashboard">Hackerrank</a></li>
<li>Any <a href="https://adventofcode.com/">&ldquo;Advent of Code&rdquo;</a> problems</li>
</ul>


<h5>D. Behavioral Questions (aka &ldquo;Soft Skills&rdquo;)</h5>

<p>Don&rsquo;t neglect this prep! Take the time to outline answers to the common behavioral questions (&ldquo;tell me about a conflict you had with a coworker&rdquo; etc.) and practice talking through them, so you have examples at your fingertips. (If your current company has certain behavioral questions they like to ask in interviews, make sure you can answer all of those.)</p>

<p>In particular, it&rsquo;s useful to workshop these answers with a friend/collegue/mentor so that you can cast difficult situations in the best light, make sure you&rsquo;re being honest without being overly critical, etc.</p>

<h3>Where to Apply</h3>

<p>This advice applies to any job hunt, but <em>especially</em> when you&rsquo;ve got limited bandwidth because you&rsquo;re still day-jobbing: <em>if you can afford to be picky with your companies, be picky!</em> Narrow your options and don&rsquo;t try to play the field&mdash;move forward with at most 3 companies you&rsquo;re excited about. (I did 5, that was doable but also pretty stressful).</p>

<p>Don’t be afraid to bow out of the process early with a given company if you&rsquo;re not excited about them. You can also always put companies on hold, and come back to them if none of your first choice companies work out.</p>

<h3>Scheduling Interviews/Timeline</h3>

<p>Do your best to keep all of your interview processes in sync with each other: first all the preliminary recruiter chats, and when you&rsquo;ve finished those, <em>then</em> all the tech screens, and <em>then</em> the onsites, etc.</p>

<p>Be up front about your timeline from the very beginning, and repeat it every chance you get. Setting expectations for &ldquo;I hope to do all my onsites the week of X and make a decision by Y&rdquo; will help your interview coordinators help you, and make it easier for you to keep all your interview processes in sync with each other. Remember that the bigger a company, the slower it probably moves, so err on the side of starting earlier with the bigger companies on your list.</p>

<h4>On Taking Vacation While Interviewing</h4>

<p>If you <em>can</em> take a whole week off of work to knock out all of your onsites, I highly recommend it! It gives you more breathing room, and looks less conspicuous than a smattering of random mid-week days off. Remember, you want to take not only enough time to do the interviews, but also enough time to rest between them.</p>

<p>A note to those with unlimited PTO: <em>take that vacation, yo!</em> Remember, you don&rsquo;t get paid out for &ldquo;unused&rdquo; vacation days, so you&rsquo;re shortchanging yourself unless you take off the time that you need.</p>

<h4>Take a Damn Break</h4>

<p>I highly, highly, <em>highly</em> recommend a break between jobs. It&rsquo;s the only time in this capitalist grind-machine that we get this much time off, so take advantage of it.</p>

<p>I mention this here because the sooner you tell companies about your start date needs, the more likely it is that they can accommodate you (and if they can&rsquo;t, you can decide whether that&rsquo;s a deal-breaker). In general, start date timelines can take the form of specific dates (&ldquo;I want to start on mm/dd/yyyyy&rdquo;) or intervals (&ldquo;I want to start six weeks after signing&rdquo;). I prefer the latter because it&rsquo;s not subject to getting messed up if interview timelines run long, but it&rsquo;s worth it to <em>keep repeating</em> to your recruiter, hiring manager, etc. (It&rsquo;s easy for someone to hear &ldquo;I want to start 6 weeks after signing&rdquo; as &ldquo;I want to start on August 1&rdquo;, and when your interviews drag out and you sign on July 15, they still think you want to start on August 1.)</p>

<h3>In the Interview</h3>

<p>There&rsquo;s plenty of tech interview advice out there that&rsquo;s way better than what I can give, but I <em>will</em> say: in your interview, don&rsquo;t shit on your current job. If you have big frustrations, get them out of your system with a friend, and then workshop diplomatic answers to standard interview questions about why you’re leaving, a time you had a conflict with a coworker, etc.</p>

<p>Also, remember that when negotiation time rolls around, “I could always just stay at my current job”is a very powerful bargaining chip. Don’t take that away from yourself even if you have no intention of staying at your current job.</p>

<h3>Congrats, You&rsquo;ve Landed an Awesome Job 🎉</h3>

<p>Give your notice, thank your current job (or don&rsquo;t), consider giving an exit interview with some honest feedback (or don&rsquo;t)&hellip; and <em>celebrate</em>! Take a damn break and relax a little between roles. If you&rsquo;ve got bandwidth, consider paying it forward by giving some mock interviews to people in your communities. If you&rsquo;re willing, consider sharing your new salary with friends and old coworkers to make this industry more transparent.</p>

<p>And take a deep breath. You did it, congrats!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>This post assumes that your day job is also in tech or some field that&rsquo;s similarly flexible in terms of hours, oversight, taking meetings/breaks/vacation, etc. If you&rsquo;re hunting for a tech job while in retail etc., I have no concrete advice for you, but godspeed and good luck, and feel free to hit me up for a practice interview.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Note that I was interveiwing as a <em>senior software engineer</em> (6 yrs. experience). I think this affected the number of companies who wanted to interview me, and the types of interview questions I got. (For instance, my interviews were more focused on system design and troubleshooting than coding and algorithms, and for more junior positions, I&rsquo;d probably expect the opposite.)<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>There are of course some toxic workplaces that are the exception to this rule. I trust you to know the answer to this question for your specific workplace.<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Spring for the pro plan for a month or two, and you can send individual meeting-booking links to all of the recruiters etc. you&rsquo;re working with, while being sure that nothing scheduled will interfere with anything on your work calendar.<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>I particularly liked using podcasts because it was interview prep I could do while out on a walk, instead of being glued to my computer<a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for Technical Interviews]]></title>
    <link href="http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/2018/03/25/interview-prep/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-25T15:17:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://maiamcc.github.io/blog/2018/03/25/interview-prep</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Life update time! After three great years at <a href="https://engineering.shopspring.com/">Spring</a>, I&rsquo;m moving on to my next adventure; in April, I&rsquo;ll be joining <a href="https://windmill.engineering/">Windmill</a> as their fifth engineer, where I&rsquo;ll be building cloud-based developer tools, as well as company culture.</p>

<p>The most frequent question I&rsquo;ve got from people upon telling them this news (after &ldquo;what the heck is Windmill?!&rdquo;) is, &ldquo;How did you prepare for your interviews?&rdquo; (And all the related questions: &ldquo;How long did you prep for?&rdquo;, &ldquo;What were your on-sites like?&rdquo;, etc.)</p>

<p>This post aims to answer those questions. Here&rsquo;s some detail on my own personal interview prep and interview process. Of course, everything here should be taken with a grain of salt, as all of this will vary widely based on you and your skills, the sorts of companies you&rsquo;re interviewing for, etc.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>How did you prep?</h1>

<h2>Resume/Soft Skills</h2>

<p>The first thing I did (because it felt like the least intimidating way to ease into the job search process) was to update my resume. I made a big list of all the things I&rsquo;d done at work since I last updated my resume, then went back over that list, pulled out the most compelling and impressive items, and wrote bullets for them. I also got several rounds of feedback from friends and collegues in the tech industry. You can never have too many eyes on your resume.</p>

<p>I also practiced talking about my work and my projects, and answering so-called &ldquo;soft skills&rdquo; questions. Cracking the Coding Interview has a handy grid to help you organize your thoughts about your projects:</p>

<p><img src="/images/ctci-interview-prep-matrix.png" alt="From Cracking the Coding Interview (4th ed.), p. 23" /></p>

<p>I <em>didn&rsquo;t</em> physically fill this out, because I&rsquo;m lazy&mdash;but I <em>did</em> go over all of this in my head, making sure I had an idea of the interesting, challenging, and conversation-worthy bits of the major bullet points on my resume.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been interviewing candidates at work for 2ish years now, so I have some idea of the questions that get asked in interviews and could think ahead about my answers to those<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>: but by far the most useful prep I did here was to have people mock-interview me. Having to answer these questions <em>out loud</em> forced me to think about them more concretely, and I could also get feedback on the things that I was saying that were more or less impressive, red-flag-y, etc. (&ldquo;If they ask you about conflicts with coworkers, tell story A, not story B, cuz in story A you resolved your disagreement, and in story B you were right and your coworker wrong and the system broke because of it, but even though you were right, it still resulted in the system breaking.&rdquo;)</p>

<h3>Preparing YOUR Interview Qs For THEM</h3>

<p>Another thing worth doing is preparing a list of questions that <em>you</em> want to ask <em>of your interviewers</em> to get a better idea about the company you may possibly work for. The better your questions for them, the more insight you can get into their workplace&mdash;and the more prepared you are with these questions, the less dumb you look in front of your interviewer.</p>

<p>I read a bunch of &ldquo;questions to ask in job interviews&rdquo; articles, grilled my friends, and put together a big doc of the questions I thought were the most informative. Some useful blog posts on the topic:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2013/12/30/questions-im-asking-in-interviews/">https://jvns.ca/blog/2013/12/30/questions-im-asking-in-interviews/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://juliepagano.com/blog/2015/08/15/job-search-retrospective/#interview-questions">http://juliepagano.com/blog/2015/08/15/job-search-retrospective/#interview-questions</a></li>
<li><a href="http://lizabinante.com/blog/getting-hired-without-getting-burned/">http://lizabinante.com/blog/getting-hired-without-getting-burned/</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Algorithms</h2>

<p>To brush up on my algos, I worked through <a href="http://interactivepython.org/runestone/static/pythonds/index.html">Problem Solving with Algorithms and Data Structures using Python</a>, making sure to ask questions about/dig deeper into anything I didn&rsquo;t understand. Most of this I skimmed because I was already familiar with it, but I made sure to note the architypal problems for each data type (&ldquo;oh, it&rsquo;s an X problem? You should use data structure Y!&rdquo;), and paid special attention to trees and graphs cuz they&rsquo;re my weak spot.</p>

<p>And then it was just looots of practice problems. Some from <em>Cracking the Coding Interview</em>, some from <a href="https://leetcode.com/">LeetCode</a>, and as much practicing with friends as I could get. The best is to get friends who actually interview developers, because they know the ins and outs of their questions better, but even just having a friend mock-interview you with CtCI or LeetCode questions is better than nothing.</p>

<p>Practicing algos Qs on your own just thinking through the solution, or writing the solution on a computer, is good. Writing it out on paper/a whiteboard is better. Practicing with a person (in a mock interview sort of capacity, where you&rsquo;re timed, they&rsquo;re giving you hints where necessary but pushing you to explain yourself) is best. Especially if technical interviews make you nervous: the more you do it, even with friends, the more used to that anxiety you&rsquo;ll be, and the better you&rsquo;ll be able to perform in the real thing.</p>

<h2>System Design</h2>

<p>Like with algos, mostly this was a matter of practice&mdash;getting friends to mock interview me with system design quesitons. I also went over some of the systems I built at work and made sure that I understood the technical choices and trade-offs there, so I could talk intelligently about it in interviews.</p>

<p>A piece of advice I got here (which I didn&rsquo;t end up taking, and it all turned out okay, but I probably should have done this anyway) was to talk to folks at other companies about their system architecture. My Achilles&#8217; heel in system design interviews has always been that I&rsquo;m only really familiar with the one or two paradigms I&rsquo;ve worked in&mdash;talking to others about <em>their</em> paradigms would have been super useful, and given me a lot more ideas to draw on.</p>

<h1>How long did you prep for?</h1>

<p>I took two weeks off of work around Christmas/New Years, and was doing a bit of prep work every day&mdash;sometimes several hours of reading or practice interviews, sometimes 15 minutes researching a company or brushing up my resume, but I tried to do <em>something</em> every day. After that, I went back to my day job and I did a bit whenever I could&mdash;some problems on LeetCode in the evening, or a practice problem coffee date with a friend over the weekend. After a few weeks of occasional practice interviews, I felt pretty prepped. My process was pretty drawn out cuz I took my time to find companies I wanted to interview for, set up those interviews, etc., so I would keep doing the occasional practice problem during that to keep in shape, but mostly I felt pretty well prepared.</p>

<h1>What was your interview schedule like?</h1>

<p>Like I said, I took a while at the beginning of this process to get my resume in order, do some research on companies and write up a big list, brush up on algos, etc.</p>

<p>I lined up a couple of phone screens early to get them out of the way (staggering them so that I wasn&rsquo;t too absent at work), and punted on the on-sites so I could cluster those around the same time.</p>

<p>I highly recommend having your first on-site (or two) be a &ldquo;warm-up&rdquo;: <em>not</em> your dream job, but either one you don&rsquo;t feel too strongly about, or one that is a real long shot and you&rsquo;re not really banking on. The idea is to have your first interview or two be a little lower stress and lower stakes. Best case scenario, you get an offer and have more leverage or a fab opportunity you didn&rsquo;t count on; worst case, you get to ease yourself back into the sometimes-grueling world of on-site technical interviews.</p>

<h1>How did you decide where to interview?</h1>

<p>The way I decide many other things: I made a big ol&#8217; doc where I kept track of recommendations from friends, collegues, the Internet, etc. I brainstormed products I&rsquo;d be interested to work on, and places friends had worked or places I&rsquo;d seen on the internet with cultures that I liked. I looked up the companies of people I enjoy on Twitter and elsewhere on the interwebs. I took suggestions from the amaaazing jobs team at <a href="https://www.recurse.com/">RC</a>.</p>

<p>And then I dug into those companies. Looked for articles on company culture, their approach to tech problems, their thoughts on diversity and whether they had women and PoC on their engineering team/in management, how many blog posts they had by women/PoC, etc. I looked on Glassdoor. If I had friends there, or friends of friends, I reached out to them to ask them if they liked it there. I hit up people in my network (esp. women) for word-on-the-street. And from all that, sortakinda got a picture of these companies and which I was or wasn&rsquo;t interested in moving forward with.</p>

<p>(I should note that an important part of this process was being clear on what I wanted out of my next company. Having a concrete idea of my own values helped me know what things to look for, which questions to ask, and which things were dealbreakers. It&rsquo;s worth spending a good chunk of time on this step, as it will inform the rest of your search. In particular, I found Key Values&#8217; <a href="https://www.keyvalues.com/culture-queries/">Culture Queries</a> a useful place to start.)</p>

<h1>Then what?</h1>

<p>Well hopefully, the offers start rolling in! Be transparent with everyone in your interview process about where you&rsquo;re at, what your concerns are, and what you need from them. Stating your needs going in sets a good precedent!</p>

<p>When you start thinking about switching jobs, be prepared for lots of last minute insurance submissions and affair-getting-in-order, and remember to take any relevant documents off your computer/email/google drive, any relevant passwords off your password manager, etc. (Pro tip: if you know you&rsquo;ll be leaving early-ish in the year, max out your Flex Spending Account and you&rsquo;ll end up with free money! It&rsquo;s a good time to buy those prescription sunglasses you don&rsquo;t reaaally need, but heck, they&rsquo;re free!)</p>

<p>As for me, I&rsquo;m taking a month off and chilling, and so very excited about it. And thennnnn&hellip; I start my new job!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m pretty psyched about this next chapter in my life, and I hope that some of the thoughts above are of use to someone. Best of luck, y&#8217;all!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Things like: &ldquo;How do you learn a new language or framework?&rdquo;; &ldquo;Tell me about a time that you failed&rdquo;; etc.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
